# JOSH MILLER

Location: Houston, TX 77598 | Phone: 281-755-5131 | Email: william.miller@att.net LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/josh-miller-65317816a/ | Github: https://github.com/joshmiller32

### **SUMMARY**

Software developer with background in financial services and advanced financial programming tools such as Python, Pandas, API interactions, Amazon Web Services, and SQL. Educated at Rice University School of Continuing Studies with a certification in FinTech. Highly motivated team player proficient with financial modeling, forecasting, and machine learning models. Ability to increase revenue and decrease costs through financial programming tools and years of financial services experience.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming:** Python 3, API Interactions, Amazon Web Services, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS **Financial Fundamentals:** Time-Series Analysis, Financial Ratios, Financial Analysis **Tools:** Scikit-learn, Numpy, Scipy, Quantopian, Pandas, Data Visualization Libraries **Machine Learning:** Algorithmic Trading, Financial Modeling, Forecasting **Blockchain:** Solidity, Ethereum, Smart Contracts, Consensus Algorithms, Cryptocurrency

## **PROJECTS**

Cryptocurrency Portfolio Analysis | <a href="https://github.com/joshmiller32/Crypto">https://github.com/joshmiller32/Crypto</a> Portfolio Analysis Developed a dashboard with other team members to determine if adding small amounts of cryptocurrency exposure to traditional investment portfolios would increase returns enough to justify the additional risk exposure using Monte Carlo Simulations to forecast returns. Tools used in this project include Plotly Express, Numpy, Pandas, PyViz, Plotly, Seaborn, TA, and iexfinance API.

Baseball Game Prediction Model | <a href="https://github.com/joshmiller32/Baseball">https://github.com/joshmiller32/Baseball</a> Predictor

Worked on a team of four to build a machine learning model that could predict the outcome of baseball games and maximize returns using inefficiencies that were observed in the betting markets. Explored multiple different machine learning algorithms to optimize performance. Tools used in this project include Pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, and Numpy.

Multi-Chain Crypto Wallet | <a href="https://github.com/joshmiller32/Multi-Chain Crypto">https://github.com/joshmiller32/Multi Chain Crypto Wallet</a>
Created a Multi-Chain Crypto Smart Wallet with 3 other team members. This crypto wallet is not just another crypto wallet. Even though it can carry out the same functionality of most wallets out there, this wallet has also the power to carry out real P2P atomic transactions, exchange between cryptocurrencies through atomic transaction in a market, and it also has a section that predicts price for the cryptocurrencies listed in the wallet through Machine Learning algorithms. Tools used in this project include python, html, css, javascript, py hd wallet, eel, grcode, clove, web3, bit, plotly, sklearn, scrypt, cryptos, multicryptos.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Rice University, Fintech Certification, Houston, TX** 

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in VBA, Python, SQL, Big Data, Ethereum, Blockchain, and Machine Learning.

## Coursera, IBM Data Science Professional Certification

Demonstrated ability to use Data Science to solve for real-world problems. Can apply Data Science methodology - work with Jupyter notebooks - create Python apps - access relational databases using SQL & Python - use Python libraries to generate data visualizations - perform data analysis using Pandas - construct & evaluate Machine Learning (ML) models using Scikitlearn & SciPy and apply data science & ML techniques to real location data sets.

University of Houston Clear Lake, Bachelor of Science – Finance, Houston, TX

## **EXPERIENCE**

Independent Agent, Self-Employed, Webster, TX

2017-2020

Call potential clients to expand existing book of business. Assess client needs through personal financial interview and recommend appropriate solutions. Explain features and benefits of recommended policies. Assist in policyholder settlement claims.

**Financial Advisor,** Compass Investment Solutions, Houston, TX 2013-2017 Acted as a leader and financial advisor. Performed financial reviews for affluent clients and recommended appropriate investment solutions. Led a team of bankers and tellers to meet their personal investment referral goals as well as led team in efforts to become licensed to sell investments. Prospected via telephone, lobby engagement, and referral generation.

- Responsible for 6 branch locations and their investment book of business ensuring compliance standards were met while maintaining consistent growth
- Met and exceeded revenue goals for each branch location through robust outbound prospecting and referral generation
- Grew investment book of business for each location by engaging new and existing clients in personal financial reviews

**Financial Solutions Advisor,** Bank of America Merrill Lynch, Houston, TX 2011-2013 Performed financial reviews for affluent banking and investment clients while recommending appropriate investment solutions. Prospected via telephone, lobby engagement, and referral generation. Led branch teams to reach their individual goals.

- Increased revenue for branch locations through team development and outbound prospecting methods
- Provided daily one-on-one meetings to help team members reach production goals.
- Educated team members on investment products and services in order to give them the confidence to generate referral prospects